<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Way of the Cross</string>

    <string name="privacy_policy_url">https://misiek198910.github.io/mojaparafia-privacy/droga_krzyzowa_privacy.html</string>

    <string name="gorzkie_zale_screen_name">Bitter Lamentations</string>
    <string name="gorzkie_zale_back_description">Back</string>
    <string name="gorzkie_zale_prev_description">Previous</string>
    <string name="gorzkie_zale_next_description">Next</string>
    <string name="gorzkie_zale_tap_to_open">Tap to open text</string>

    <string name="menu_way_of_cross_title">Way of the Cross</string>
    <string name="menu_way_of_cross_subtitle">Meditations on the Lord\'s Passion</string>
    <string name="menu_gorzkie_zale_title">Bitter Lamentations</string>
    <string name="menu_gorzkie_zale_subtitle">Three parts of the devotion</string>
    <string name="menu_news_title">News</string>
    <string name="menu_news_subtitle">Latest news, change announcements</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="news_feed_title">Latest News</string>
    <string name="news_feed_back">Back</string>
    <string name="news_feed_empty">No new messages</string>
    <string name="news_feed_no_title">Untitled</string>
    <string name="news_feed_learn_more">Learn more</string>

    <string name="privacy_policy_screen_name">Privacy Policy</string>
    <string name="privacy_policy_back">Back</string>

    <string name="settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="settings_back">Back</string>
    <string name="settings_language">Change Language</string>
    <string name="settings_subscriptions">Subscriptions</string>
    <string name="settings_privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</string>
    <string name="settings_select_language">Select Language / Wybierz język</string>
    <string name="settings_lang_pl">Polish</string>
    <string name="settings_lang_en">English</string>

    <string name="way_of_cross_screen_name">Way of the Cross</string>
    <string name="way_of_cross_back">Back</string>
    <string name="way_of_cross_prev">Previous</string>
    <string name="way_of_cross_next">Next</string>
    <string name="way_of_cross_tap_to_read">Click to display text</string>

    <string name="subs_title">Premium Subscription</string>
    <string name="subs_back">Back</string>
    <string name="subs_card_title">App Support</string>
    <string name="subs_description">Your subscription helps us develop the \"My Parish\" project and maintain servers without intrusive ads.</string>
    <string name="subs_benefit_no_ads">No ads throughout the app</string>
    <string name="subs_benefit_support">Support for app development</string>
    <string name="subs_status_label">STATUS</string>
    <string name="subs_status_active">ACTIVE</string>
    <string name="subs_status_inactive">INACTIVE</string>
    <string name="subs_manage">Manage subscription</string>
    <string name="subs_restore">Restore purchase</string>
    <string name="subs_footer_info">Subscription renews automatically. You can cancel at any time in Google Play settings.</string>

    <string name="subs_monthly_button">Monthly - %s</string>
    <string name="subs_annual_button">Yearly (7 days trial) - %s</string>
    <string name="load_data">Fetching price…</string>


    <string-array name="gorzkie_zale_titles">
        <item>Part I</item>
        <item>Part II</item>
        <item>Part III</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="station_titles">
        <item>Station I: Jesus is condemned to death</item>
        <item>Station II: Jesus carries His cross</item>
        <item>Station III: Jesus falls the first time</item>
        <item>Station IV: Jesus meets His Mother</item>
        <item>Station V: Simon of Cyrene helps Jesus carry the cross</item>
        <item>Station VI: Veronica wipes the face of Jesus</item>
        <item>Station VII: Jesus falls the second time</item>
        <item>Station VIII: Jesus meets the women of Jerusalem</item>
        <item>Station IX: Jesus falls the third time</item>
        <item>Station X: Jesus is stripped of His garments</item>
        <item>Station XI: Jesus is nailed to the cross</item>
        <item>Station XII: Jesus dies on the cross</item>
        <item>Station XIII: Jesus is taken down from the cross</item>
        <item>Station XIV: Jesus is laid in the tomb</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gorzkie_zale_czesci">
        <item>Bitter Lamentations – Part One</item>
        <item>Bitter Lamentations – Part Two</item>
        <item>Bitter Lamentations – Part Three</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="station_contents">
    <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
The sentence issued by Pilate under pressure from the crowd becomes the beginning of the final testimony of God\'s love for the world. The Roman governor tries to wash his hands of it and stand aside, but there is no escaping the reality of the cross. Facing this mystery, we gain the certainty that we too must not wash our hands of the responsibility for our faith.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, O Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who co-suffered, O Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
Jesus, true God and innocent man, stands before the court. Although he has committed no sin, he silently accepts the unjust sentence condemning him to death. In his wounded body and silent submission, we see his immense love for each of us. He consents to this cross so that we might receive forgiveness. Let us look to Him and learn humility in the face of injustice.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you redeemed the world</b><br/><br/>
The weight of the cross, exhaustion, and physical pain cause Jesus to fall to hard ground for the first time. Although he could plead for help, he endures the mockery and humiliation in silence. This fall is not a sign of defeat, but of infinite love and complete submission to the Father\'s will.<br/><br/>
With each painful step, the Savior teaches us how to rise from our own weaknesses, stumbles, and sins, remaining faithful to God until the very end.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you deigned to redeem the world.</b><br/><br/>
On the path of suffering, the Son meets the Mother. Mary cannot reverse the sentence or lift the burden from Jesus\' shoulders, but her presence becomes a tremendous support for Him. In that single gaze, deep human pain is mingled with complete trust in God. The sword of sorrow, foretold years ago, now pierces the heart of the Mother, who faithfully follows her child to the very end.<br/><br/>
Contemplating this encounter, let us learn from Mary to remain close to those who suffer, even when all we can offer them is our silent and loving presence.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, O Christ Jesus, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you, who suffered with us, O Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For by your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
When Jesus\' strength weakens under the weight of a wooden beam, soldiers force Simon of Cyrene, who is coming from the field, to help a condemned man carry the cross. This bystander suddenly becomes the closest companion of the Savior in suffering. Although he initially accepts this duty out of compulsion, the closeness of the suffering Christ changes his heart.<br/><br/>
This station teaches us that an encounter with the cross, even an unwanted and sudden one, can become the beginning of a profound faith. Let us open our hearts to helping others in their daily hardships.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, O Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, O Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
Amidst the crowd of onlookers and soldiers, a brave woman, Veronica, appears. She approaches the tortured Savior and gently wipes His blood-stained and sweaty face with a cloth. In reward for this simple, empathetic gesture, Jesus leaves the imprint of His Holy Face on the canvas. This scarf becomes a lasting testimony to the fact that the smallest gesture of kindness toward a suffering neighbor is never forgotten.<br/><br/>
Let us learn from Saint Veronica the courage to help and to see the face of Christ in every person who needs our support, compassion, or presence.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
The path becomes increasingly difficult, and the Savior\'s physical strength drastically diminishes. Jesus falls under the weight of the cross for the second time. Although surrounded by a crowd of onlookers, He remains completely alone in this painful experience. Out of love for humanity, He accepts this extreme exhaustion and humiliation, rising from the ground to continue His mission of redemption.<br/><br/>
This subsequent fall reminds us how difficult the struggle with recurring sins can be. However, Christ rises to give us hope and the strength to rise from our own daily falls.<br/><br/>
<i>Who suffered wounds for us, O Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And You, who suffered with us, O Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you redeemed the world</b><br/><br/>
On the Way of the Cross, Jesus encounters women weeping over his fate. Despite his own immense suffering, the Savior stops and addresses them, calling them to look deeply into their own hearts and consciences. He reminds them that the true cause for sadness should be sin, which distances man from God, and its consequences for future generations.<br/><br/>
This Station calls us to abandon superficial compassion and undertake the sincere effort of conversion. Let us ask for the grace of living in truth and the courage to transform our morals.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, O Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, O Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
At the foot of Golgotha, when the goal is already within reach, the utterly exhausted Jesus falls under the weight of the cross for the third time. This is a moment of complete human helplessness, in which every step seems impossible. Nevertheless, guided by infinite love and obedience to the Father, the Savior gathers the last of his strength to rise and complete the work of salvation on the hill of the cross.<br/><br/>
This final fall teaches us that there is no situation or sin from which we cannot rise, if we trust in God\'s love. Let us pray for perseverance in moments of life\'s greatest discouragement.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, O Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, O Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore You, Lord Jesus, and we bless You</b><br/>
<b>L. That through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
Upon reaching the execution site, the soldiers ruthlessly strip Jesus of the garments that had clung to his dried wounds. The Savior is publicly stripped and exposed to the ridicule of the crowd. In this extreme humiliation, by surrendering his wounded and desecrated body, Jesus reveals the most wonderful love and absolute obedience to the Father\'s will. Every new wound and every drop of blood becomes a silent testimony to the price of our redemption.<br/><br/>
Contemplating this humiliation, let us pray for purity of heart and respect for the dignity of every human being, remembering the great value each of us has in the eyes of God.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world</b><br/><br/>
The most terrible stage of the suffering begins. Jesus is thrown onto wooden beams, and sharp nails pierce his arms and legs. Every movement, every muscle tension, and terrible physical pain tear his body apart. In this inhuman suffering and exaltation above the earth, the Savior does not curse his tormentors. From his lips fall words full of infinite mercy and forgiveness: "Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do."<br/><br/>
This station teaches us a radical love that can forgive even in moments of the greatest hurt. Let us pray for hearts capable of reconciliation and free from the desire for revenge.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, O Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, O Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you.</b><br/>
<b>L. For through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
For three hours, Jesus agonizes in unimaginable torment, suspended between heaven and earth. He experiences extreme abandonment, loneliness, and thirst, crying out in anguish to his Father. His arms, stretched wide on the cross beam, become a sign of ultimate victory – the entire mystery of Redemption lies within them, for they embrace and embrace all sinful humanity. After fulfilling everything, he surrenders his spirit into the hands of God.<br/><br/>
In the silence of this station, let us stand beneath the cross and give thanks for the gift of freedom born of this saving death. You, Lord, gave everything so that we might have life.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you</b><br/>
<b>L. That through your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world.</b><br/><br/>
The sacrifice is complete. The lifeless, limp body of Jesus is carefully taken down from the cross and placed in the arms of his grieving Mother. Mary receives her Son in profound, dignified silence. This moment painfully recalls the moments in Bethlehem, yet now she holds in her hands the price for the world\'s salvation. Simeon\'s prophecy about the sword that would pierce her soul has been fulfilled to the very end, and she still perseveres in her silent entrustment to God\'s will.<br/><br/>
Let us learn from the Blessed Mother to remain with God in moments when, humanly speaking, all seems lost. May her faith strengthen us in moments of life\'s losses and mourning.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[
<b>K. We adore you, Lord Jesus, and we bless you</b><br/>
<b>L. For by your cross and suffering you have redeemed the world</b><br/><br/>
The Savior\'s body, wrapped in clean linen, is hastily placed in a new tomb carved into the rock. A heavy stone is rolled before the entrance, and the profound silence of Holy Saturday falls around. However, this tomb does not become a symbol of final defeat. Descendant into the bowels of the earth, the Son of God challenges death itself, preparing the morning of the Resurrection. From now on, every grave is no longer a place of despair, but becomes a gateway to eternity.<br/><br/>
This station calls us to unwavering hope. Even when the darkness of the grave reigns in our lives, let us believe that God has the power to transform every darkness into the light of new life.<br/><br/>
<i>You who suffered wounds for us, Jesus Christ, have mercy on us!</i><br/>
<i>And you who suffered with us, Mother of Sorrows, intercede for us.</i>
]]></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gorzkie_zale">
   <item><![CDATA[
<big><b>EXHORTATION (Awakening)</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Come to us, O bitter lamentations, and penetrate our hearts.<br/>
2. Dissolve, my eyes, and let the springs of mournful tears flow.<br/>
3. The sun and stars grow faint and cover themselves in mourning.<br/>
4. The Angels weep bitterly, and who can express their sorrow?<br/>
5. Hard rocks are split asunder, and the dead rise from their graves.<br/>
6. What is happening, I ask? All creation trembles!<br/>
7. At the pain of Christ\'s passion, unspeakable grief takes hold.<br/>
8. Strike, O Jesus, without delay, at the hard rocks of our hearts!<br/>
9. My Jesus, in the blood of Your wounds, wash my soul from my sins!<br/>
10. I cool the heat of my heart as I enter the abyss of Your passion.<br/><br/>

<big><b>INTENTION</b></big><br/><br/>
With the help of God\'s grace, we proceed to meditate on the passion of our Lord Jesus Christ. We offer it to the Heavenly Father for the honor and glory of His Divine Majesty, humbly thanking Him for His great and incomprehensible love for the human race, in that He deigned to send His Son to suffer cruel torments and undergo death on the cross for us. We also offer this meditation in honor of the Most Blessed Virgin Mary, the Mother of Sorrows, and in honor of the Saints who distinguished themselves by their devotion to the Passion of Christ. In the first part, we shall consider what the Lord Jesus suffered from His prayer in the Garden of Gethsemane until His unjust accusation before the court. We offer these insults and outrages to the same Lord, suffering for us, for the Holy Catholic Church, for the Supreme Shepherd with all the clergy, and furthermore for the enemies of Christ\'s cross and all unbelievers, that God may grant them the grace of conversion and repentance.<br/><br/>

<big><b>HYMN</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Grief grips the soul and the heart feels pain, as sweet Jesus prepares for death; He kneels in the Garden, pouring out bloody sweat, my heart faints.<br/>
2. The Lord of holiness is kissed by a wicked disciple, and bound with ropes by a cruel soldier! Jesus submits to these bonds for our sake, giving Himself up to death.<br/>
3. An untamed crowd strikes and pushes Him, mercilessly from this side and that, pulling Him by the hair: the King from on high endures in patience.<br/>
4. Lips previously bruised are now covered in blood, as a soldier strikes with an armed glove; soon the love of the heart turned into mournful sighing.<br/>
5. Oh, that the heart would dissolve in tears, for it has foully offended You, my Jesus! I am sorry, oh, I am sorry for my heavy wickedness for the sake of Your love!<br/><br/>

<big><b>LAMENT OF THE SOUL OVER THE SUFFERING JESUS</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Jesus, led to a cruel slaughter, Silent Lamb sought by enemies, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
2. Jesus, sold for thirty pieces of silver by an ungrateful disciple, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
3. Jesus, oppressed by heavy sorrow and grief before death, as You Yourself confessed, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
4. Jesus, covered in a stream of bloody sweat during prayer in the Garden, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
5. Jesus, betrayed by a deceitful kiss from the unworthy Judas, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
6. Jesus, bound with thick ropes by a lawless soldiery, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
7. Jesus, insultingly reviled by the common folk before Annas\' court, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
8. Jesus, shamefully dragged by the hair through the streets to Caiaphas\' court, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
9. Jesus, struck on the face by the wicked Malchus with a criminal hand, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
10. Jesus, unjustly presented as a deceiver by two false witnesses, my beloved Jesus!<br/><br/>
<b>Hail to Thee, praise to Thee, for our sake exhausted and blood-stained. Be adored! Be glorified! O infinite God!</b><br/><br/>

<big><b>DIALOGUE OF THE SOUL WITH THE SORROWFUL MOTHER</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Ah! I, a Mother so sorrowful! Unbearable pain grips me. A sword pierces my heart.<br/>
2. Why, beloved Mother, is your heart so heavily troubled? Why do you tremble so?<br/>
3. Why do you ask me? I am all in a faint, I cannot speak for grief, blood floods my heart.<br/>
4. Tell me, O my Virgin, why does your face turn pale? Why do you shed bitter tears?<br/>
5. I see that my beloved Son in the Garden is all covered in a bloody torrent of sweat.<br/>
6. O Mother, fount of love, let me feel the force of your grief! Grant that I may weep with you.<br/><br/>

<i>Lord Jesus, crucified for us, have mercy on us! (3 times)</i>
]]></item>

        <item><![CDATA[
<big><b>EXHORTATION (Awakening)</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Come to us, O bitter lamentations, and penetrate our hearts.<br/>
2. Dissolve, my eyes, and let the springs of mournful tears flow.<br/>
3. The sun and stars grow faint and cover themselves in mourning.<br/>
4. The Angels weep bitterly, and who can express their sorrow?<br/>
5. Hard rocks are split asunder, and the dead rise from their graves.<br/>
6. What is happening, I ask? All creation trembles!<br/>
7. At the pain of Christ\'s passion, unspeakable grief takes hold.<br/>
8. Strike, O Jesus, without delay, at the hard rocks of our hearts!<br/>
9. My Jesus, in the blood of Your wounds, wash my soul from my sins!<br/>
10. I cool the heat of my heart as I enter the abyss of Your passion.<br/><br/>

<big><b>INTENTION</b></big><br/><br/>
In the second part of the meditation on the Lord\'s Passion, we shall consider what the Lord Jesus suffered from His unjust accusation before the court until His cruel crowning with thorns. We offer these wounds, insults, and outrages to the same suffering Jesus, asking Him for the prosperity of our Homeland, for peace and harmony among all nations, and for ourselves the forgiveness of sins, the turning away of calamities and temporal misfortunes, and especially pestilence, famine, fire, and war.<br/><br/>

<big><b>HYMN</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Behold, O soul, how God loves you, how He does not spare Himself for you. Yet your wickedness torments Him more than the executioner\'s cruelty.<br/>
2. The Lord of all creation stands before the judge, a silent Lamb in great contempt; for the white robe in which He is dressed, He is called a fool.<br/>
3. For my wickedness, His back is severely scourged; come, sinners, behold they prepare for us from the Blood of Jesus a spring of living water for the heart\'s refreshment.<br/>
4. Let worldly pride predict what it will, weaving a wreath of roses for its brow; the King wounded by thorns is adorned in scarlet for mockery!<br/>
5. Oh, that the heart would dissolve in tears, for it has foully offended You, my Jesus! I am sorry, oh, I am sorry for my heavy wickedness for the sake of Your love!<br/><br/>

<big><b>LAMENT OF THE SOUL OVER THE SUFFERING JESUS</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Jesus, innocently proclaimed by the common folk as a thief worthy of death, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
2. Jesus, so foully spat upon on Your beautiful face by malicious murderers, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
3. Jesus, denied thrice under oath by Peter out of great fear, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
4. Jesus, dragged like a murderer to Pilate\'s court by cruel executioners, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
5. Jesus, mockingly laughed at by Herod and his courtiers, O Heavenly King, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
6. Jesus, mockingly dressed in a white robe for greater derision and shame, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
7. Jesus, unmercifully lashed with whips at the stone pillar, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
8. Jesus, crowned with a wreath of thorns through cruel mockery, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
9. Jesus, unworthily dressed in purple for derision by the soldiers, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
10. Jesus, struck on the head with a reed, King of Sorrows, mocked by the people, my beloved Jesus!<br/><br/>
<b>Hail to Thee, praise to Thee, for our sake insulted and all blood-stained. Be adored! Be glorified! O infinite God!</b><br/><br/>

<big><b>DIALOGUE OF THE SOUL WITH THE SORROWFUL MOTHER</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Ah, I see my Son stripped at the pillar, scourged with rods!<br/>
2. Holy Virgin, entreat for me, that I may have the mark of Your Son\'s wounds engraved on my heart!<br/>
3. Ah, I see how immensely sharp thorns wound His head! My soul faints!<br/>
4. O Mary, share with me the passion of Your Son, wounded by sharp thorns!<br/>
5. Oh, that I, a sorrowful Mother, could take Your cross upon my shoulders, my Son!<br/>
6. I pray, O unique Virgin, let me always carry the cross of Your Son in my heart!<br/><br/>

<i>Lord Jesus, crucified for us, have mercy on us! (3 times)</i>
]]></item>


        <item><![CDATA[
<big><b>EXHORTATION (Awakening)</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Come to us, O bitter lamentations, and penetrate our hearts.<br/>
2. Dissolve, my eyes, and let the springs of mournful tears flow.<br/>
3. The sun and stars grow faint and cover themselves in mourning.<br/>
4. The Angels weep bitterly, and who can express their sorrow?<br/>
5. Hard rocks are split asunder, and the dead rise from their graves.<br/>
6. What is happening, I ask? All creation trembles!<br/>
7. At the pain of Christ\'s passion, unspeakable grief takes hold.<br/>
8. Strike, O Jesus, without delay, at the hard rocks of our hearts!<br/>
9. My Jesus, in the blood of Your wounds, wash my soul from my sins!<br/>
10. I cool the heat of my heart as I enter the abyss of Your passion.<br/><br/>

<big><b>INTENTION</b></big><br/><br/>
In this final part, we shall consider what the Lord Jesus suffered from the moment of His crowning with thorns until His heavy death on the cross. We offer these blasphemies, outrages, and insults inflicted upon Him for hardened sinners, that the Savior may stir their straying hearts to penance and true improvement of life, and for the souls suffering in purgatory, that the merciful Jesus may extinguish their fire with His holy blood; we further pray that He may obtain for us at the hour of death contrition for our sins and happy perseverance in God\'s grace.<br/><br/>

<big><b>HYMN</b></big><br/><br/>
1. O cold soul, why do you not burn? My heart, why do you not tremble entirely? Out of fiery love, your Jesus pours out blood in abundance.<br/>
2. When the fire of love so inflames Him, He casts the shameful tree upon His shoulders; fainted, Jesus kneels under the cross, groaning and moaning.<br/>
3. He becomes obedient to the cruel executioners, allowing His hands and feet to be pierced; He hangs on the cross, our dear Savior endures severe pain!<br/>
4. O sweet tree, lower the Body to us now, so it may no longer hang upon you! We shall lay Him honorably in the tomb and keep our mourning.<br/>
5. Oh, that the heart would dissolve in tears, for it has foully offended You, my Jesus! I am sorry, oh, I am sorry for my heavy wickedness for the sake of Your love!<br/>
6. May honor be Yours, my Jesus, in eternity for Your insults, torments, and outrages, which You, the only Son of God, willingly suffered without guilt!<br/><br/>

<big><b>LAMENT OF THE SOUL OVER THE SUFFERING JESUS</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Jesus, impiously compared by the common folk to a criminal among thieves, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
2. Jesus, unjustly condemned to death on the cross for mankind by Pilate, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
3. Jesus, exhausted by the heavy burden of the cross on the road to Calvary, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
4. Jesus, nailed to the shameful tree with blunted nails, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
5. Jesus, openly crucified on the tree of shame between two thieves, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
6. Jesus, mockingly laughed at by those standing around and passing by, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
7. Jesus, derided with blasphemies by the wicked thief hanging beside Him, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
8. Jesus, given bitter gall and vinegar to drink in His great thirst, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
9. Jesus, in His immeasurable love, further pierced by a spear even after death, my beloved Jesus!<br/>
10. Jesus, honorably buried in the tomb by Joseph and Nicodemus, my beloved Jesus!<br/><br/>
<b>Hail to Thee, praise to Thee, for our sake exhausted and blood-stained. Be adored! Be glorified! O infinite God!</b><br/><br/>

<big><b>DIALOGUE OF THE SOUL WITH THE SORROWFUL MOTHER</b></big><br/><br/>
1. Ah, I, a sorrowful Mother, stand under the cross in sadness, grief penetrates my heart.<br/>
2. O Mother, let me truly, looking upon the cross with sorrow, weep bitterly with You.<br/>
3. Truly, truly my Beloved prepares for His passing! Thus, I also die with Him!<br/>
4. I desire, Mother, to stay with You, to share in Your mourning for the death of Your Son.<br/>
5. Sweet Jesus has closed His speech, already He bows His head toward the earth, He bids farewell to His Mother!<br/>
6. O Mary, I ask You, let me bear the wounds of Jesus and contemplate them in my heart.<br/><br/>

<i>Lord Jesus, crucified for us, have mercy on us! (3 times)</i>
]]></item>

    </string-array>

</resources>